dancersinlight.com 2013-12-26

# Privacy Policy | SmugMug

**Date of Last Revision: September 27, 2013**

At SmugMug, Inc. ( ** _"SmugMug"_** , **_"we"_** or **_"us"_** ), we are passionately committed to the privacy of our customers.

This Privacy Policy ( ** _"Privacy Policy"_** ) explains how information about you is collected, used and disclosed by SmugMug. This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect when you use our website, www.smugmug.com, our mobile application and other products and services that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the **_"Services"_** ).

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the date at the top of the policy and, in some cases, we may provide you with additional notice (such as adding a statement to our homepage or sending you an email notification). We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy whenever you access the Services to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy.

For information about how to change your privacy preferences for your photo galleries, please see: <http://help.smugmug.com/customer/portal/articles/1229910>.

## Collection of Information

### Information You Provide to Us

We collect information you provide directly to us. For example, we collect information when you:

  * Create an account and subscribe to our digital photography, media hosting or other services;
  * Purchase photo prints or other products or services;
  * Participate in a survey, contest or sweepstakes;
  * Contact us by email for any reason, such as to request help with the Services or to provide us with your comments/feedback;
  * Post information in connection with your photos and galleries (e.g., in a photo caption) or in other forums or interactive areas of the Services; or
  * Otherwise communicate with SmugMug.

The types of information we may collect include your name, email address, postal address, phone number, fax number, credit card information and other contact or identifying information you choose to provide. 

You have the option of telling us how you wish to be identified in connection with your photos, galleries, comments and elsewhere using the Services. If you choose to use your real name (or include any identifying information as part of your "nickname") that information will be publicly displayed through the Services. Therefore, please use caution in determining how you wish to be identified in using the Services.

### Information We Collect Automatically When You Use the Services

When you access or use our Services, we automatically collect information about you, including:

  * Log Information: We log information about your use of the Services, including the type of browser you use, access times, pages viewed, your IP address and the page you visited before navigating to our Services.
  * Device Information: We collect information about the computer or mobile device you use to access our Services, including the hardware model, operating system and version, screen resolution, color and depth, unique device identifiers and mobile network information.
  * Location Information: We may collect information about the location of your device each time you access or use one of our mobile applications or otherwise consent to the collection of this information. For more details, please see "Your Choices" below.
  * Information Collected by Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies: We use various technologies to collect information, and this may include sending cookies to your computer or mobile device. Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in device memory that help us to improve our Services and your experience, see which areas and features of our Services are popular and count visits. We use cookies to keep you logged in to the Services, to count the number of unique computers using the Services and to record your user preferences. We may also collect information using web beacons (also known as "tracking pixels"). Web beacons are electronic images that may be used in our Services or emails and help deliver cookies, count visits, understand usage and campaign effectiveness and determine whether an email has been opened and acted upon. For more information about cookies, and how to disable them, please see "Your Choices" below.

### Information We Collect From Other Sources

We may also obtain information from other sources and combine that with information we collect through our Services. For example, if you create or log into your account through a social media site, we will have access to certain information from that site, such as your name, account information and friends lists, in accordance with the authorization procedures determined by such social media site. We may receive updated information about you, such as an updated billing address, from the financial institution issuing your credit card in connection with our billing for the Services.

## Use of Information

We may use information about you for various purposes, including to:

  * Provide, maintain and improve our Services;
  * Provide and deliver the products you order, process your subscription to the Services and other transactions, and send you related information, including confirmations and invoices;
  * Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts and support and administrative messages;
  * Respond to your comments, questions and requests and provide customer service and support for the Services;
  * Facilitate your use of, and our administration and operation of the Services;
  * Communicate with you about products, services, offers, promotions, rewards, and events offered by SmugMug and others, and provide news and information we think will be of interest to you;
  * Monitor and analyze trends, usage and activities in connection with our Services;
  * Personalize and improve the Services and provide advertisements, content or features that match user profiles or interests;
  * Process and deliver contest entries and rewards;
  * Link or combine with information we get from others to help understand your needs and provide you with better service; and
  * Carry out any other purpose for which the information was collected.

SmugMug is based in the United States and the information we collect is governed by U.S. law. By accessing or using the Services or otherwise providing information to us, you consent to the processing and transfer of information in and to the U.S. and other countries. ****

## Sharing of Information

We may share information about you as follows or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy:

  * With vendors, consultants and other service providers who need access to such information to carry out work on our behalf;
  * If you purchase prints or other products from one of our subscribers (e.g., a professional photographer whose site is maintained or hosted by SmugMug), so that such subscriber may provide you with assistance or answer questions you may have in connection with your purchases;
  * In response to a request for information if we believe disclosure is in accordance with any applicable law, regulation or legal process, or as otherwise required by any applicable law, rule or regulation;
  * If we believe your actions are inconsistent with the spirit or language of our user agreements or policies, or to protect the rights, property and safety of SmugMug or others;
  * In connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company; and
  * With your consent or at your direction, including if we notify you through our Services that the information you provide will be shared in a particular manner and you provide such information.

We may also share aggregated or anonymized information that does not directly identify you.

### Social Sharing Features

The Services may offer social sharing features and other integrated tools which let you share actions you take on our Services with other media, and vice versa. The use of such features enables the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the entity that provides the social sharing feature. For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social sharing features, please visit the privacy policies of the entities that provide these features.

### Advertising and Analytics Services Provided by Others

We may allow others to serve advertisements on our behalf across the Internet and to provide analytics services. These entities may use cookies, web beacons and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Services and other websites, including your IP address, web browser, pages viewed, time spent on pages, links clicked and conversion information. This information may be used by SmugMug and others to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, deliver advertising and content targeted to your interests on our Services and other websites and better understand your online activity. For more information about Internet-based ads, or to opt out of having your web browsing information used for behavioral advertising purposes, please visit [www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) and [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices).

### Security

SmugMug takes reasonable measures to help protect information about you from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

### Your Choices

#### Account Information

You may update, correct or delete information about you at any time by logging into your online account or emailing us at [help@smugmug.com](mailto:help@smugmug.com). You may delete your account or terminate your subscription pursuant to SmugMug's Terms of Use, but note that we may retain certain information as required by law or for legitimate business purposes. We may also retain cached or archived copies of information about you for a certain period of time.

#### Location Information

When you first launch any of our mobile applications that collect location information, you will be asked to consent to the application's collection of this information. If you initially consent to our collection of location information, you can subsequently stop the collection of this information at any time by changing the preferences on your mobile device. You may also stop our collection of location information by following the standard uninstall process to remove all of our mobile applications from your device.

#### Cookies

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies. Removing or rejecting browser cookies does not necessarily affect third party flash cookies used in connection with our Services. To delete or disable flash cookies please visit [www.adobe.com/products/flashplayer/security](http://www.adobe.com/products/flashplayer/security) for more information. Please note that if you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect the availability and functionality of our Services.

#### Promotional Communications

You may opt out of receiving promotional communications from SmugMug by following the instructions in those communications or by emailing us at [help@smugmug.com](mailto:help@smugmug.com). If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional communications, such as those about your account or our ongoing business relations.

#### Your California Privacy Rights

California law permits residents of California to request certain details about how their information is shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please contact us at [help@smugmug.com](mailto:help@smugmug.com).

#### Contact Us

We welcome your feedback. If you have any comments or concerns about this Privacy Policy or would like to contact us for any reason, you may reach us via email at [help@smugmug.com](mailto:help@smugmug.com).
